<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-10-10T23:08:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Inside A Vfd</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/02/inside-a-vfd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inside A Vfd" /><published>2023-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/02/inside-a-vfd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/02/inside-a-vfd.html"><![CDATA[<p>Inside a Variable Frequency Drive (VFD), the DC switching aspect plays a crucial role in converting the incoming AC power into DC power, which is then used to generate the variable frequency and voltage output required to control the speed of an induction motor. Here’s a general explanation of the DC switching aspect in a VFD:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Rectification: The first step in the DC switching aspect is rectification. The incoming AC power from the mains is fed into a rectifier circuit within the VFD. The rectifier circuit converts the AC power into DC power by using power electronic devices, typically diodes or thyristors. These devices conduct current in only one direction, allowing them to convert the alternating current into a pulsating direct current.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Filtering: The rectified DC voltage produced by the rectifier circuit is not perfectly smooth and contains pulsations or ripples. To smooth out these pulsations and obtain a stable DC voltage, a filtering circuit is used. This circuit typically consists of capacitors connected in parallel with the DC bus. The capacitors absorb the pulsating component of the rectified voltage and provide a more constant DC voltage.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>DC Bus: The filtered DC voltage is then supplied to the DC bus of the VFD. The DC bus acts as a storage and distribution system for the DC power. It provides a stable voltage level that serves as the primary source for generating the variable frequency and voltage required by the motor.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Inverter: The inverter stage is where the DC switching aspect comes into play. The inverter converts the DC power from the DC bus back into AC power with variable frequency and voltage. This is achieved by using power electronic devices called Insulated Gate Bipolar Transistors (IGBTs) or other types of transistors.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Pulse Width Modulation (PWM): The inverter stage utilizes a technique known as Pulse Width Modulation (PWM) to control the output frequency and voltage. PWM involves rapidly switching the transistors on and off at high frequencies. By adjusting the duration or width of the ON and OFF states of the transistors, the effective voltage and frequency delivered to the motor can be varied.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Output to Motor: The variable frequency and voltage output generated by the inverter are then supplied to the motor’s stator windings. The changing frequency and voltage control the rotational speed and torque of the motor, allowing precise speed control in various industrial applications.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>The DC switching aspect within a VFD is responsible for the conversion of the incoming AC power to stable DC power and subsequently reconverting it back to AC power with variable frequency and voltage. This process enables the VFD to provide precise speed control and other advanced motor control features.</p>]]></content><author><name>ross</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inside a Variable Frequency Drive (VFD), the DC switching aspect plays a crucial role in converting the incoming AC power into DC power, which is then used to generate the variable frequency and voltage output required to control the speed of an induction motor. Here’s a general explanation of the DC switching aspect in a VFD:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Plc Programmers Job</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/02/plc-programmers-job.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plc Programmers Job" /><published>2023-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/02/plc-programmers-job</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/02/plc-programmers-job.html"><![CDATA[<p>The job of a PLC (Programmable Logic Controller) programmer in 2021 involves designing, developing, and maintaining programs that control and automate industrial processes. PLCs are digital computers used to control machinery and equipment in industries such as manufacturing, botanicals, and water / wastewater.</p>

<p>Program Development: PLC programmers create and develop ladder logic and structured text code that defines the behavior of the PLC, such as controlling inputs and outputs, monitoring sensors, and executing logical operations.</p>

<p>System Configuration: They configure the hardware and software components of the PLC system, including the communication interfaces, input/output modules, and network connections. This involves selecting the appropriate components and setting up the system to ensure reliable and efficient operation.</p>

<p>Testing and Debugging: PLC programmers conduct rigorous testing of their programs to identify and rectify any errors or bugs. They simulate various scenarios to ensure the program behaves as expected and troubleshoot any issues that arise during the testing phase.</p>

<p>Integration: PLC programmers collaborate with other professionals, such as electrical engineers or automation specialists, to integrate the PLC system into larger industrial systems. This may involve connecting the PLC to sensors, motors, actuators, or other control devices.</p>

<p>Maintenance and Upgrades: They perform regular maintenance tasks to ensure the continued functioning of the PLC system. This includes monitoring system performance, diagnosing faults, and implementing corrective measures. PLC programmers may also be responsible for updating or upgrading existing programs to improve efficiency, add new functionality, or adapt to changing requirements.</p>

<p>Documentation: PLC programmers document their work, including program logic, system configurations, and troubleshooting procedures. This documentation helps in maintaining and updating the system in the future and serves as a reference for other team members.</p>

<p>Stay Updated: Keeping up with the latest trends, technologies, and standards in the field of industrial automation is essential for PLC programmers. They need to stay informed about advancements in PLC hardware and software, industrial communication protocols, safety standards, and best programming practices.</p>]]></content><author><name>ross</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The job of a PLC (Programmable Logic Controller) programmer in 2021 involves designing, developing, and maintaining programs that control and automate industrial processes. PLCs are digital computers used to control machinery and equipment in industries such as manufacturing, botanicals, and water / wastewater.]]></summary></entry></feed>